<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>smol[weblog]</title>
  <link>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/</link>
  <description>A place where I write text files. Started at December 2024.</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 22:29:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<item>
    <title>My smol blogging platform made in C</title>
    <link>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/general/start-blog-project.html</link>
    <guid>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/general/start-blog-project.html</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[I was not satisfied with any of the blogging platfom so I made my own with black jack and h00kers.
It is a single C file that compiles to less than 12KB of Linux binary.

You interact with it with files. Project has this structure:
* /working_dir/
* /generate/
* /public_html/
* /templates/

/working_dir/ is where all the text files are organized in folders. Each folder is a tag.
/generete/ is where the engine looks for a new files to cranch. It will move it to the /public_html/ folder and update the index file.
/templates/ keeps template files for the layout of the blog.

It is simple, lean and easy to use.

How to compile:
* gcc smolblog.c -o smolblog
* upx smolblog

Usage:
* ./smolblog
* copy text files into the /generate/ folder
* serve contents of /public_html/


This project was an experiment. A simple solution to my unconventional problem. It worked out better than I anticipated. 
Thanks to C and lack of external dependencies it is portable.

If you are interested in details, github link is in the footer.

Have fun!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>My IDE Setup</title>
    <link>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/programming/myidesetup.html</link>
    <guid>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/programming/myidesetup.html</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2024 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[I spend most of my codding time in VSCode on Linux (various distributions).
It has all the extensions I need, it is fast, and available on any modern OS. This last part is important to me as I can continue my work on any systems I use, including Windows work machines.

Extensions I use:
* Code Spell Checker
* GitHub Copilot
* Hex Editor
* Remote - SSH
* x86 and x86_64 Assembly
* C/C++
* various "Cyberpunk 2077" Themes

I got Source Control opened on left and Copilot on right. Terminal on bottom if needed.
I'm using Copilot as interactive documentation and writing comments.
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Test post</title>
    <link>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/testing/another.html</link>
    <guid>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/testing/another.html</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is made using smolBlog platform.
This post was updated!

Huray!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Free form writing #1</title>
    <link>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/freeform/free1.html</link>
    <guid>https://smol.p1x.in/weblog/posts/freeform/free1.html</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2024 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Just a moment of me and the text file. Im writing whatever I'm thinking at present moment.
What make the text file special for me is the same as writing by hand on paper for writers.
Text files are easy to process and share between different operating systems and architectures. ASCII is universal.

I'm not writing a big article nor book chapter. I can brake any rule, skip proof reading, formatting. All I'm doing is writing. In a zen mode, no distractions. A closest experience you can have to the real typewriter.

The key is a keyboard. A good one. That doesn't mean expensive, just not cheap. I got Microsoft Ergonomic, the one split in half and curved in. Superb keeb.]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>